Brian Kim (Dong Hyun)

Irvine, CA 92602 (949) 285-1898 brian@bdhk.dev

linkedin.com/in/bdhk github.com/briandhkim bdhk.dev

Summary

Full-stack web developer with nearly six years of experience. Skills extend beyond technical discipline, excelling in collaboration with diverse groups of people, including developers, QAs, business analysts, client success managers, and more. Seasoned in resolving unusual issues and delivering effective solutions.

Technical Skills

Languages:

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Ruby

Frameworks, libraries, & database:

Laravel, jQuery, Vue.js, React, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Tools, methodologies, & other:

Git, GitHub, Docker, Herd, Postman, axe DevTools, Jira, Confluence, Bamboo, Heroku, NewRelic, Scrum, Kanban, accessible web development, Test Driven Development (TDD)

Experience

Sr. Software Engineer | BeSmartee | Jul. 2021 - Apr. 2024

Engineering Team | Feb. 2023 - Apr 2024

- Created proof-of-concept applications for the company's V2 initiatives using new technology stack: React, Next.js,
 Laravel, and PostgreSQL
- Spearheaded internal tools development reducing redundant tasks for multiple stakeholders, increasing workflow efficiency by 99%
- Diagnosed areas for optimization with the existing PHP codebase and implemented refactored solutions, decreasing runtime for some of the long running scripts from minutes to milliseconds
- Collaborated with diverse stakeholder groups including engineering, product, client success, and more to adhere to intricate laws and compliance requirements pertaining to mortgage lending practice
- Mentored developers as well as members outside of engineering department to strengthen interdepartmental rapport
- Orchestrated resolutions of several critical incidents thereby saving relationship with the company's top clients

Service Team | Jul. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Engineered new microservices utilizing test-driven development (TDD) across two different technology stacks:
 Laravel and Ruby on Rails
- Reinforced development using SOLID and DRY principles

PDT, Deployment Specialist | Jul. 2021 - Jul. 2022

 Supervised major version releases, assessing risks and potential points-of-failure to intercept issues before they impact production services

- Introduced the deployment guideline with safeguards based on analysis of common, recurring problems, eliminating 100% of preventable defects and improving development standards across the entire engineering department
- Facilitated onboarding of seven new developers for the engineering department

Software Engineer | BeSmartee | Feb. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Production Defect Team (PDT) | Oct. 2020 - Jul. 2021

- Triaged thousands of defect tickets to establish efficient resolution for high volume of system defects
- Resolved hundreds of urgent, production-level defects minimizing outage incidents for critical business operations
- Analyzed several critical, misguided issues and presented root cause analysis to stakeholders, thereby averting lawsuits and saving relationships with top clients

Implementation Team | Feb. 2019 - Oct. 2020

- Orchestrated the encryption algorithm upgrade used by the existing PHP application and attained seamless transition to stronger security standards
- Lead frontend development of a new, single-page application (SPA) using Vue.js and TailwindCSS focused on versatile user experience
- Developed applications with Laravel framework, enforcing TDD to create scalable codebase with zero reported bugs

Jr. Software Engineer | BeSmartee | Jul. 2018 - Feb. 2019

UX Team | Jul. 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Enriched the existing **jQuery** and **PHP** application with **web accessibility** improvements

Education

University of California - Los Angeles (UCLA) | Bachelor of Arts: Psychology | 2016

Awards and Recognition

- 6th Person of the Year | BeSmartee | 2022
- *All Star Engineering* | BeSmartee | 2021
- Rookie of the Year | BeSmartee | 2018

References

Available upon request.